Lluis Artus | Dr.

Harald Løvenskiolds vei 4 – 0760 Oslo – Norway

Born: 16th of December, 1992

☑ Ilartuss7@gmail.comin Iluis-artus-suarez※ Ilartuss7¶ GitHub¶ V0c1H8IAAAAJ

\$\text{https://lluisartussuarez.github.io/}



Personal Statement

PhD in computational chemistry, specializing in the simulation of catalytic systems. I have been studying CO_2 hydrogenation mechanisms for seven years and enantioselective hydrogenation of olefins for two years. Using density functional theory, classical molecular dynamics, and microkinetic modeling, I can study the role of catalysts in the reactions. That information is essential to identify favorable and detrimental factors that determine the reaction rates and allow the development of faster and more stable catalysts.

Machine learning applied to theoretical chemistry is rising in popularity. Therefore, last year, I started training myself in it. I have been reading about state-of-the-art ML techniques, attending an ML conference applied to computational chemistry, and, in November 2023, enrolling in IBM's online course on Machine Learning. There, I learned about exploratory data analysis, regression, classification, and unsupervised models, but it will also cover genetic models and deep learning. I look forward to implementing what I learned into a practical application.

Professional experience

| Stockholm, Sweden |
|-------------------|
| 2022-2024 |
| |
| |
| Scandinavia |
| 2022-2024 |
| |
| 2018-2021 |
| |
| |
| 2022 |
| |
| 2019 |
| |
| |
| 2022 |
| |
| |

| Valladolid University, Spain Group of Martin Jaraiz. Microkinetic modelling. June – July | 2018 |
|--|--|
| ICIQ, Spain Group of Feliu Maseras. Modelling of single electron transfers. | 2015-2016 |
| GMMF, Spain (Not paid) Group of E. Carolina Sañudo. Synthesis and characterization of magnetic | 2014-2015 and fluorescent molecules. |
| Others | |
| Frenchie Bistro Waiter | Oslo, Norway Sept. 2021 – Feb. 2022 |
| Skogstad Hotel *** | Hemsedal, Norway |
| Waiter and housekeeper | Summer. 2021 |
| Hotel Port-Bó*** | Palafrugell, Spain |
| Receptionist | Summers 2013 – 2015 |
| Hotel & Spa Mas de Torrent ***** | Torrent, Spain |
| Receptionist | Summers 2009 – 2010 |
| Education | |
| Academic education | |
| Oslo University | Oslo, Norway |
| Ph.D. Chemistry Thesis: "Computational study on the deaminative hydrogenation of amid complexes" | 2016-2021 les catalyzed by base metal |
| Rovira i Virgili University | Tarragona, Spain |
| M.Sc. Chemistry | 2015-2016 |
| Thesis: "Computational characterization of the mechanism of the reactio and aryl halides" | n between Fe(I) complexes |
| Barcelona University | Barcelona, Spain |
| B.Sc. Chemistry | 2010-2015 |
| Thesis: "Synthesis and characterization of coordination compounds with | _ |
| Courses and Certifications | |
| Unsupervised Machine Learning Online. IBM course of >23h. June | 2024 |
| Supervised Machine Learning: Classification Online. IBM course of >24h. April | 2024 |
| Singularity workshop Stockholm, Sweden. February 12 | 2024 |
| Supervised Machine Learning: Regression Online. IBM course of >20h. February | 2024 |
| Exploratory Data Analysis for Machine Learning Online. IBM course of >14h. December | 2023 |

Introduction to GPUs course Stockholm, Sweden. October 12-13

Alpha fold v2.0 and RoseTTAFold Workshop

2023

2021

8th MOLCAS Users' Workshop

Uppsala, Sweden. Nov. 20-24



Computational chemistry

Reaction mechanism exploration

Software: Gaussian, Jaguar (Schrodinger), COPASI, Acuchem

Rational catalyst design of organometallic catalysts.

Microkinetic modelling for the design and interpretation of experimental kinetic experiments and for the evaluation of theoretical models.

Drug discovery and material science

Software: Amber, Gromacs, CP2K

Forcefield parametrization of organometallic systems

Free energy calculations: FEP, EVB, umbrella sampling, metadynamics Properties calculations: binding energies, diffusion coefficients, viscosities...

Cheminformatics

Software: RDKit, OpenBabel, molSimplify

Automatic interpretation of chemical databases

Automatic generation of molecular structures for future processing (e.g. machine learning)

Others

Software: NBO6, NCIPLOT, OpenMolcas, Chemcraft, PHI, ioChem-BD

Experimental chemistry.....

Basic training in

Good laboratory practices, NMR, MS, UV-Vis, FT-IR, Spectrofluorometry, HPLC, GC and SQUID.

Informatics.....

I have worked with supercomputers and computer clusters for eight years, at a user level.

I am comfortable with python, and have basic knowledge of C++, Fortran, bash, awk and seq.

The python libraries I use most are os, sys, shutil, pandas, numpy, scipy, matplotlib, seaborn, sklearn, rdkit, molSimplify and OpenBabel.

Most of my programming has been scripting for workflow automation or data analysis.

I have recently started studying machine learning. So far, I have completed IBM online courses on "Exploratory Data Analysis" and "Machine Learning regression models".



Publications

Seven articles published in scientific journals. H index of five. Cited more than a hundred times. Five first-authorships.